MARAT KANZAFAROV

Curriculum Vitae

Contact Information

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/marat-k-021a3a5b

Email: m.kanzafarov@gmail.com

Kaggle: https://www.kaggle.com/mknzfr

Personal Statement

Result-oriented backend team lead with 15 years of experience in the IT industry, a keen eye for detail results in solid coding and trustworthy software programmes. Advanced skills of mentoring developer teams, maintaining high-loaded projects. Strong analytical, troubleshooting and problem solver skills. Focused on business requirements.

Employment History

2017-present

Computer vision project #2, Team lead

Developing backends, processing from hundreds of thousands to millions of images, managing experiments, training models, evaluating metrics, parsing logs, drawing plots, R&D prototyping.

Technology stack: Annoy, Celery, Docker, Faiss, Flask, Git, Mahotas, Matplotlib, MMDetection, NLTK, NMSLIB, NumPy, OpenAI CLIP, OpenCV, Pandas, Pillow, PostgreSQL, Pydicom, Python, Python multiprocessing, Pytorch, pytorch-image-models (timm), RabbitMQ, Redis, SciPy, scikit-image, scikit-learn, seaborn, segmentation_models.pytorch, Tensorboard, Tensorflow, umap-learn, various YOLOs

2016-2017

Computer vision project #1, Backend team lead

Designed and implemented the backend of the computer vision project.

Technology stack: Celery, Docker, dlib, Flask, Git, NumPy, OpenCV, Python, scikit-image, Tensorflow

2015-2016 NCT, Team lead

Designed and implemented mail and storage systems. Worked closely with the frontend development team and product owner. Conducted code reviews of the backend development team and interviewed 100+ job applicants.

Technology stack: FastCGI, Git, Nginx, Openstack Swift, Perl, PostgreSQL, Redis

2013-2015

Westudy, Backend team lead

Designed and implemented the backend of the educational platform.

Technology stack: Git, Nginx, Perl (Mojolicious), PostgreSQL

2013

Yandex, Software developer

Developed the Direct API.

Technology stack: Git, Perl, MySQL

2011-2013

Search engine, Senior software developer

Designed and implemented the backend for the inner assessors' website, which was used for improving search engine result pages.

Technology stack: Apache, Hadoop, PHP (Symfony), Perl, PostgreSQL, SVN

2009-2011

CityInfo, Software developer

Designed and implemented the backend of the informational website.

Technology stack: Apache, GeoIP, Nginx, PHP (Symfony), PostgreSQL, SVN

2007-2009

Mail.ru Group, Software developer

Redesigned and implemented the backend of **auto.mail.ru** (one of the most visited websites in the CIS), car marketplace, image storage and processing, xml parsing.

Developed the Q&A web service **otvet.mail.ru** and network community platform **forum.*.mail.ru**.

Technology stack: Apache, ImageMagick, Memcached, MySQL, Nginx/ow, PHP, Perl, SVN

Additional Professional Experience

2020-present

Kaggle Experience, Kaggle expert

Competitions and results

- Plant Pathology 2021: Top 1%
- Plant Pathology 2020: Top 2%
- Cassava Leaf Disease Classification: Top 7%
- Global Wheat Detection: Top 10%

Education

1999-2005

Lomonosov Moscow State University (Faculty of Physics, Computer Methods in Physics)

Hobbies

AR/VR, Chess, GameDev, Robotics, Traveling